Hello friends, welcome to Tippon Sites.
In today's video, we will talk
about the Cashless Everywhere scheme.
GIC has launched a scheme called
Cashless Everywhere. Cashless Everywhere
means that we
can get our treatment done cashlessly in any hospital.
What was happening before was that we used to get
our treatment done cashlessly only by going to network hospitals. In this
case, if we went to a non-network hospital for
our treatment, then we had to make all the payments
in cash and later
all the bills were
processed. Its name is Cashless Everywhere, which
means you can get your treatment done
free of cost in any hospital, you
can get it done cashless, you will not have to make any payment.
So, I am going to tell you about this scheme
in detail later. So, please
watch the video till the end,
like the video, subscribe to the channel and
press the bell icon
so that you keep getting notifications of new videos. So
let's start the video
[Music] The
name of the organization which launched this scheme is GIC i.e. General Insurance
Council. It was formed in 2001.
How can we use the scheme of Cashless Everywhere launched by IRDAI and GIC for getting
our treatment done?
Some conditions have also been kept for it, so
what are its conditions, the first
condition is that the hospital where you will go for
your treatment should be non-network,
it should be at least a 15-bedded hospital, that is, a
hospital with 15 beds should be at
least, if it is 10 or 12, then
this facility will not be applicable there, so
this is the first condition, the second condition
is if you are getting any emergency treatment,
you have been admitted in the emergency, then
within 48 hours of getting admitted in the emergency, you will have to
intimate the insurance company, that is, you will have to
inform them that I am getting
my treatment done in this non-network hospital,
so you will have to give this information
to the insurance company, but if
you are getting any planned treatment, then
what is there in it that you will have to
inform the insurance company 48 hours before getting admitted,
in the plan, for example, if there is a surgery, like the
treatment of surgery  If they undergo
any treatment in the plant surgery,
we will have to
give the intimation of the same to the insurance company 48 hours before admission. So there are two
conditions, this 48-hour emergency
and the plant treatment.
I have explained both of them to you. The
hospital which will provide the Cashless Everywhere facility should be
registered with the local state authority and should be
registered with the medical authority.
If it is not a registered hospital, then
it will not be applicable there.
Who can avail the benefits of the Cashless Everywhere scheme?
Existing policy holders can avail it. Those with
new policies can also avail the benefits of this scheme. But you will
not have to pay any additional charge separately. You will
not have to pay any premium separately.
This is very good news, but it will take
some time to be implemented and to be fully integrated into the system because there will be
some issue in pricing with the non-network hospitals of the insurance company.
Some insurance companies have
put details on their website that
they want to offer this scheme, they
want to give the benefit of this scheme to their policy holders.
You can know about it by visiting a website.  I'm going to
explain. The Future Generali
website has detailed
how Future Generali
Health Insurance policyholders can
take advantage of the Cashless Everywhere scheme.
Gradually, all
insurance companies and TPAs ​​will
update this on their websites and
send information to hospitals. The
main issue will be related to the rates,
as insurance companies
don't offer high rates. They will offer
much lower rates than what hospitals charge in cash. It will take
some time for these rates to be finalized. This scheme is
good, but it will take time to fully implement.
It's very good,
and you'll get a lot of benefits in the future.
Let
me go to the Future Generali website and
show you how they've posted a letter and
uploaded a PDF. It details the
Cashless Everywhere scheme, explaining
how
policyholders
can benefit from it. First, we need to
google "Everywhere Future Generali," so
click on it.  If you do this, this PDF will
open in front of you.
In this, the insurance company has written that
we are very happy to inform our policy holders
that we are going to
give you the benefit of cashless everywhere and
they have mentioned some of its conditions below,
so you people have to read them. Here below,
they have written about cashless everywhere, the conditions, these one, two, three,
four such points have started here, so in that
also the same things are written which I
told you, like in the 48 years it is written
that in case of emergency you people have to
inform within 48 hours and in the plan you have to
inform 48 hours in advance, so both the
things are written, in the third it is written
that it will depend on the terms of the policy, the
entire treatment is also written in it
that all the cashless facilities will come
under what is written in the terms of the policy,
in the fifth point it is written that the
link of the documents etc. which will be sent for the cashless facility is given in it, that of the pre-payment form  You
people have to click from here and see it, it
is written further on the sixth point, the request
of cashless facility, cashless facility, non-
network hospital should be sent through the
website, you can also go to the website and click on this link and
send the request to them,
after that it is written in the seventh point, the hospital
which is not a network company, provides letter of
consent to extend cashless facility,
physical document of one page MoU must be
accepted by the
hospital, a copy of the MoU has to be signed between the hospital and the
insurance company,
without that this scheme will not be implemented anywhere, so
you people have to wait
because the
rates related to the treatment have to be decided between the hospital and the insurance company,
like room rent or any
surgery or any procedure, it will take
some time in deciding the rates, so
you people have to wait a little,
this scheme has been implemented but it will take some
more
time to be implemented completely, so you should maintain some patience,
in the eighth point it is written that
all  All the
rules of the reserve company are
kept reserved, all the rules are in their hands, they will give treatment as per their
wish, that is, after
checking your treatment and everything, they
can also deny it, it is
written in the ninth point that if you people have any
problem, then you can call and
talk here, you can write an email, so
they have put this on the website of Future Generali,
gradually other companies will also
update their websites and will put everything
in detail about the Cashless Everywhere scheme,
so whoever has the
health card of which company, go to that company's
website and check yourself, mostly the
terms and conditions that I have mentioned will be the same,
still you people can verify yourself,
talk to the customer care
and you can also go to the nearby hospital
which is in the non-network and
confirm once whether the
facility of Cashless Everywhere has been implemented there or
not, or whether we will get its benefit or
not, so in today's video
I have explained to you guys in detail about a scheme of GIC called Cashless
Everywhere,
still if you have
any question in your mind then please
write to me in the comment section, apart from this if you have any query regarding your
health insurance claim then
you
can share that query with me, I will
answer that too, you will definitely get
any new update related to Cashless Everywhere scheme on
this channel, so please
subscribe to the channel,
like the video, press the bell icon so that
you keep getting notification of new videos, so
see you in the next video, till then
hello